# Eshan Taneja

## Specialist Salesforce Engineer

### **About Me**

Professional salesforce certified developer having 6 years of experience. Comprehensive knowledge of platform development, agile methodologies, cloud services, and web-based applications in the salesforce platform. Have worked with several clients from different industries like insurance, non-profit, healthcare, recruitment, gaming, etc.

## **Speciality**

- 6 years of professional experience in SFDC development.
- Professional in salesforce.com/force.com development and configuration including advanced apex/aura framework/ LWC / visual force as well as a managed package, unlocked package, lightning apps, lightning design system, API integrations, profiles, record sharing, sales cloud, service cloud, community builder, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Expert in Agile framework, and DevOps tools like Jira, Bitbucket, Ant, Jenkins.
- Good problem-solver, able to quickly grasp complex systems and identify opportunities for improvements and resolution of critical issues.
- Good team player and also have the ability to work independently.
- Worked on small projects and also on large public releases for large companies.

## **Experience**

#### Junglee Games India Pvt Ltd | Specialist Salesforce Engineer

Apr 2022 - Present

- Built a Case Automation such as case acknowledgment, case assignment, auto solve
  of cases, user sync from external system, integration with Kafka, customer experience
  survey, enablement of cases for new games just using custom metadata
  configurations, case archival to AWS S3, etc have used flows, and triggers, batch apex.
- Provided a solution to CX for Approve or Decline KYC within the salesforce using the lightning component which is integrated with the external system also used Omni channel for allocating KYC requests to the agents.
- Built Einstein Case Classification model for the cases where the users don't enter the
  appropriate dispositions or we don't get any disposition from email to case due to
  which the agent has to update their values manually which is time-consuming. Also
  need to make sure that all automation should run after the Einstein case classification
  model runs.

#### NEC Software Solutions (India) Pvt Ltd | Software Engineer Sep 2021 - Mar 2022

- Created the solution for approving members and syncing them to an external database using MuleSoft API. Have used lightning web components, Rest APIs, and Triggers.
- Enabled the Email-to-case for different teams and created the sharing rules for cases to make them private from other teams.

## Contact



etaneja003@gmail.com



+91 9565140555 Gurgaon



<u>Portfolio</u>



- LWC
- Aura
- Apex
- Triggers
- Integration
- Web Services
- Asyn Apex (Batch/Future/Queue able)
- Record Level Security
- Flow/Process
   Builder/Workflow
- · SOQL/SOSL
- Validation Rules
- Deployment

#### ITC Infotech Pvt ltd | Associate IT Consultant

Jul 2020 - Aug 2021

## **Certifications**

- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer II
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I
- Salesforce Certified Administrator
- Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder
- Did Classic to Lightning migration project that included the complete setup of the lightning environment from the very beginning like designing the flexipages, components, javascript button conversion to quick actions, the home page, etc. Also needed to set the apps for five different teams based on their profiles having different tabs, record types, lightning pages, etc.
- Ops Team Setup, In this we've to set up the five new teams in their
  organization. It includes the very basic setup of salesforce users
  like user roles, profiles, record level access, object access, sharing
  rules, record types, process builder, Tenfold Integration, and
  automation. We've to configure all these for 54 users.

#### **Education**

- MCA | 2018, Krishna Institute of Engineering and Technology | Ghaziabad, UP
- BCA | 2015, SS College | Shahjahanpur, UP

#### Dean Infotech Pvt Ltd | Salesforce Developer

Feb 2020 - Jun 2020

Built a solution to auto-assign the users to the roles. The client
has two methods for allocating the role to the user Round Robin
and the Dependent. There is a configuration page where the
property is defined for roles like Users, Algo, Dependent users, etc.

#### Cloud Analogy Softech Pvt Ltd | Senior Salesforce Developer Jan 2018 - Jan 2020

- Designed a solution for the Donation management system using the Salesforce NPSP package. Have created a public site that is integrated into the customer website for collecting donations for different causes like Food, Water, Education, etc. The site is integrated with payment systems like Direct Debit and Stripe. Have used Aura components, visual force pages, payment integration, and batch apex for managing recurring donations.
- Rate Calculator, the requirement was to calculate the premium
  on the basis of the US postal code we're using Smart City API. Also
  created multiple communities where end user can select the
  premium. The flow of the rating tool is completely dynamic based
  on the user's choices. We provided the salesforce public
  community for external users and created a partner community
  for internal users.
- Broker Registration, My responsibility was to make a fully automated system for the end customer to register himself as an agency with a questionnaire. After that, using email service, we're sharing appointment packet links on the basis of State of an agency and assigning a manager to the agency. We also implemented an e-sign feature on a form. Once the questionnaire is approved by their manager then again, the Appointment packet is sent back to the end user on the basis of their state.

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above mentioned.

Place: Gurugram Eshan Taneja